Travis Black

Full Stack Developer | Operational Excellence

With a decade of experience in operation efficiency and excellence, I am now turning my career to the technology field, focusing on Full Stack Development. I adapt to learn new skills quickly and efficiently.

travisjblack93@gmail.com 979-618-1440

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tr avis-black-b262681ab/ https://github.com/TravisJBlack

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRITO LAY

Maintenance Apprentance

Rosenberg, Texas, United States | Jul 2019 - Dec 2020

- Performed preventative maintenance on entire packaging department.
- · Completed machine upgrades to eliminate safety hazards for the team.
- Enhanced design for linear railing for the packaging machines to decrease repair time from two hours to 15 minutes.
- · Conducted emergency maintenance for packaging department.
- Rebuilt vacuum pumps in house saving the company \$15,000 in repair costs.

FRITO LAY

Site Expert Trainer

Rosenberg, Texas, United States | Aug 2015 - Dec 2020

- Trained classes of new Packaging Machine Operators across the site.
- Executed multiple refresher trainings.
- Owned Packaging Machine Operator capability by performing audits and giving feedback.
- · Created a program to manage and repair packaging weighing system to reduce grams given away of product.

FRITO LAY

Packaging Specialist

Rosenberg, Texas, United States | Jun 2015 - Jul 2019

- • Managed shift of packaging machine operators.
- Performed shift pre-shift and mid-shift meetings reviewing KPMs such as efficiencies and schedule attainment.
- Coached operators on performance and gave guidance on correct processes.
- Collaborated with managers to ensure all KPMs, safety, and food safety guidelines were met.
- Owned CMS program, which reduced film waste across the site.

SKILLS

- React.js
- REST APIs
- Express.js
- Node.js
- PostgreSQL
- jQuery
- SQL
- Mongo DB
- MERN Stack
- JavaScript
- AppDynamics
- Git
- GitHub
- Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap (Framework)
- Chakra UI
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
- HTML5

EDUCATION

Certificate

Computer Software Engineering

The University of Texas at Austin

Feb 2024 - Aug 2024

Awards

Top Back End Developer